Mihaela Younas

Junior SoftWare Developer



07496-590-582

mihaelavounas55@gmail.com

in LinkedIn | Github

As a Lead Junior Full-Stack Web Developer for Vell Magazine and co-founder of Rex Gadgets, an E-commerce store, I have honed my skills in developing web applications using Python, Django, Flask, React, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. With over 9 years of experience in managerial and administrative roles within the retail sector, I possess a proven track record of leadership and team productivity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript

Front-End: React, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Design-Thinking

Back-End: Django, Flask, Django-REST, API, PostgreSql

Testing: Jest, Pytest, Unit-testing,(Pycharm and Docker)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Volunteer at Vell Magazine (April 2023 - Present)

 Successfully complete tasks and deliverables using Jira to ensure timely and high-quality results. Contribute to Vell Magazine as an Agile Methodology-focused volunteer while leveraging React.js UI/UX skills to enhance the user interface and overall user experience.

Full Stack Web Developer, Code Institute (Feb 2022 - April 2023)

As a Full-Stack Developer graduate from Code Institute, I have a comprehensive skill set in front-end development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, and React, as well as back-end development using Django, Flask, Django-REST, API, PostgreSql.. During my time at Code Institute, I worked on several projects. With experience in testing using React and Jest, I am confident in my ability to contribute to any team.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS, Portfolio

WeShare API, Github

 Implemented a robust Python-Django Rest Framework API for a media app, ensuring efficient data validation and seamless data storage in ElephantDB. Proficient in complex validations and optimizing database operations for enhanced performance and scalability.

WeShare, Github | Demo

• Developed a cutting-edge social media app using ReactJS, CSS, and React-Bootstrap for engaging posts and meaningful connections. Expertise in validation, API requests, and seamless user experience.

SecondScoop, Github | Demo

• Developed SecondScoop, an imaginative dessert shop website, with event organization, reservation booking, and interactive blogging capabilities. Leveraged Python-Django, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS for a visually appealing platform. Enabled seamless content management, user engagement, and error handling for a smooth user experience.

My Virtual Doctor, <u>Github</u> | <u>Demo</u>

• Developed My Virtual Doctor, a seamless appointment system using Python logic. Handled input errors for a smooth user experience. Implemented efficient appointment management with Google Spreadsheets

Brain-Wizzz, <u>Github</u> | <u>Demo</u>

• Created Brain Wizz, an immersive memory game leveraging advanced JavaScript logic and captivating visual design. Developed an interactive user interface that seamlessly handles user events and provides an engaging gaming experience. Combined expertise in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to deliver a fully responsive and visually appealing website

Rex Removals, Github | Demo

• Developed Rex Removals, a captivating website connecting users with a premier furniture moving company. Leveraged HTML and CSS for an aesthetically pleasing design and showcased expertise in responsive web design for optimal user experience.

REX GADGETS, E-Commerce (Sep 2018 - Present)

• Establishing from scratch an E-Commerce site with a partner, reaching 700+ orders per month, and generating traffic for over 1000 of clients. Managing 10000 pieces stock of Mobile accessories, Researching mobile accessories products that sell best within the market and researched multiple Vendor Prices

B&K ESTATES, Estate Agent/Negotiator (Feb 2013 - Jan 2015)

• Negotiated with clients ,answered calls. I would get clients everyday from the database and contact them and try to get approval for their rentals, I Made ads to promote properties and managed viewings. Used company software to get the ads posted on different websites like Rightmove, Zoopla, company websites

EDUCATION

University Of Lower Danube, Romania (July 2011 - July 2012)

• Diploma in Food Science and Technology: This Program covers a wide range of topics related to food science, including food chemistry, food processing, and food product development.